1

4136-3642-7051, v. 1.6

Freelancer Privacy Policy

Welcome to YunoJuno's freelancer privacy notice. YunoJuno respects your privacy and is committed

to protecting your personal data. This privacy notice will inform you as to how we look after your

personal data when you visit our website (regardless of where you visit it from) and tell you about

your privacy rights and how the law protects you. This privacy policy is mainly directed at freelancers

who are using the website. If you don't fall into that category of user, don't worry, it also tells you how

we use personal information generally.

Last updated: 16 July 2021

INDEX 1 IMPORTANT INFORMATION AND WHO WE ARE............................................................................ 1

2 THE DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU....................................................................................................... 2

3 HOW IS YOUR PERSONAL DATA COLLECTED? ........................................................................................ 3

4 HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA .................................................................................................... 4

5 DISCLOSURES OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA.............................................................................................. 8

6 INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS................................................................................................................. 9

7 DATA SECURITY...................................................................................................................................... 9

8 DATA RETENTION ................................................................................................................................. 10

9 YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS............................................................................................................................ 10

10 GLOSSARY.......................................................................................................................................... 11

1 IMPORTANT INFORMATION AND WHO WE ARE

Purpose of this privacy notice

This privacy notice aims to give you information on how YunoJuno collects and processes your

personal data through your use of this website, including any data you may provide through this

website when you register or use our services.

It is important that you read this privacy notice together with any other privacy related notice(s) we

may provide on specific occasions, so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your

personal data. This privacy notice supplements any other notices and is not intended to override

them.

Controller

YunoJuno Limited is the controller and responsible for your personal data.

We have appointed a data privacy manager who is responsible for overseeing questions in relation

to this privacy notice. If you have any questions about this privacy notice, including any requests to

exercise your legal rights, please contact the data privacy manager using the contact details below.

Contact details

Company name YunoJuno Limited

Contact name Data Privacy Manager

2

4136-3642-7051, v. 1.6

Email address privacy@yunojuno.com

Postal address Waverley House, 9 Noel Street, London W1F 8GQ

Changes to the privacy notice and your duty to inform us of changes

This version was last updated on the date at the top of the privacy policy, and historic versions can

be obtained by contacting us.

It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us

informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.

Third-party links

This website may include links to third-party websites, such as personal online portfolios, and social

media sites that individuals may choose to share. Clicking on those links or enabling those

connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these

thirdparty websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website,

we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.

2 THE DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU

Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that

person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous

data).

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have

grouped together follows:

Category Data collected includes

Identity data first name, last name, username, date of birth and (because we have to report it

to HMRC) the gender you identify with

Contact data email address and telephone numbers

Profile data information you have uploaded as part of your YunoJuno profile, including job

title, short biography, skills, recommendations, portfolio/code base links and

work/freelance history, as well as any client compliments you have chosen to

add to your YunoJuno profile

Financial

data

registered company/business address, company information, business bank

account details

Assignment

data details about brief responses, booked assignment, conversations about briefs

and assignments, details of timesheets and approvals, that have been created

through use of the website, and any feedback provided through the website

Marketing

data

your marketing and communications preferences, as well as details of any

marketing you have been sent by or on behalf of us or our partners

3

4136-3642-7051, v. 1.6

Technical

data internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time

zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system

and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this website

Community

data

conversations you have in the YJ Member Slack group or responses you make to

community surveys

Usage data information about how you use our website, products and services

We also collect, use and share aggregated data such as statistical or demographic data for any

purpose. Aggregated data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal

data in law as this data does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may

aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature.

However, if we combine or connect aggregated data with your personal data so that it can directly or

indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance

with this privacy notice.

We do not collect any special categories of personal data about you (this includes details about your

race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions,

trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we

collect any information about criminal convictions and offences. To the extent that you choose to

provide any of these types of personal data via the website, you do this entirely of your own choosing

and we will not have any way of identifying that this is special category data.

If you fail to provide personal data

To provide our services with you, and for us to comply with the law, we will need to obtain personal

data from you. If we ask you to provide your personal data, and you choose not to, this may mean that

you cannot make use of the services provided on our website. If this occurs, we will inform you.

3 HOW IS YOUR PERSONAL DATA COLLECTED?

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:

Direct interactions

You may give us your Identity, Contact, Profile and Financial Data by filling in forms or by

corresponding with us by post, phone, online, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you

provide when you:

• create an account on our website

• add or amend your work/experience history

• update or amend your profile information, including by choosing to add client compliments

to your profile

• ask us questions or give us some feedback (including via the website, the YJ Members slack

group or our surveys)

Automated technologies or interactions

As you interact with our website, we may automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment,

browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies, and other similar

technologies. Please see our Cookie Policy for further details.

Third parties or publicly available sources

We may receive personal data about you from various third parties and public sources as set out

below:

4

4136-3642-7051, v. 1.6

• Technical Data from the following third parties: New Relic, Sentry

• Identity and Contact Data from verification service providers such as Onfido (who will use

data brokers or aggregators to carry out their services)

• Identity and Contact data from publicly available sources such as the Electoral Register and

Companies House

• Assignment Data from clients giving feedback

The complete list of third party providers the company uses is in Disclosures of your personal data

below. Some of these providers are global companies, and we do not control how they operate – at

any given time, they will have operations inside and outside the UK. Where we can choose in our

contract with them if your data is held inside or outside the UK, we will choose inside the UK. More

information may be found in International transfers below.

4 HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your

personal data in the following circumstances:

• Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into, or have entered into, with

you. For example, to provide you with the services via our website.

• Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests

and fundamental rights do not override those interests. For example, to enable us to provide

our services to you on a personalised basis and develop our services for the future. Or to

provide our freelancers and clients with services to help them comply with their own legal or

regulatory obligations (e.g. under IR35). Or to liaise with your umbrella company, if you are an

umbrella freelancer.

• Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation. For example, to meet the

requirements of being an ‘employment business’ under UK law and in our statutory reporting

to HMRC.

See the Purposes for which we will use your personal data below to find out more about the

purpose/activity and the types of lawful basis that we will rely on to process your personal data.

Generally, we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data other than in

relation to the use of certain cookies and sending direct marketing communications to you via email

or text message. You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by contacting us

or updating your preferences directly. We send our marketing emails using Mailchimp.

Purposes for which we will use your personal data

We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal

data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate

interests are where appropriate.

Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the

specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us if you need details about the

specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground

has been set out in the table below.

Purpose/Activity Lawful basis for processing including basis of

legitimate interest

5

4136-3642-7051, v. 1.6

To register you as a new user Performance of a contract with you

Necessary to comply with a legal obligation

(e.g. verification of your identity, how you

operate as a freelancer)

Necessary for our legitimate interests (e.g.

keeping business records of our users)

To deliver our services to you, including via our

website, to:

• Enable you to create your profile in our

freelancer database

• Enable our client to promote their

freelance opportunities to our

freelancer database generally

• Enable you to receive and respond to

briefs which clients looking for

freelancers may make available to you

Performance of a contract with you

Necessary to comply with a legal obligation

Necessary for our legitimate interests (e.g.

company credit check and the administration

of our business, to show your published client

compliments on our website, communications

and social media)

• Keep your profile updated, including

your freelancer score and (if you

choose to publish it there) your client

compliments

• Promote your services to potential

clients via our website, campaigns and

social channels (including as a

highlighted individual freelancer)

• Enable you to participate in any IR35

assessment a client may be

undertaking

• Administer contracts, timesheets and

invoicing for assignments agreed

between you and a client (including via

Giant Business Connect Limited for

Inside IR35 assignments – see here)

• Administer payment to you for any

assignment you undertake (including

via Giant Business Connect Limited for

Inside IR35 assignments (see here) or

via your chosen umbrella company, if

you are an umbrella freelancer)

To make suggestions and recommendations

to you about things that may be of interest to

you (including briefs from our clients or

updated parts of our services)

Necessary for our legitimate interests (e.g. to

develop our services and grow our business)

6

4136-3642-7051, v. 1.6

To manage our relationship with you which will

include:

• Notifying you about changes to our

terms or privacy policy

• Dealing with queries and feedback

from you

Performance of a contract with you

Necessary to comply with a legal obligation

Necessary for our legitimate interests (e.g. the

administration of our business)

To administer and protect our business and

this website (including troubleshooting, data

analysis, testing, system maintenance,

support, reporting and hosting of data)

Necessary for our legitimate interests (e.g. for

running our business, provision of

administration and IT services, network

security, to prevent fraud)

Necessary to comply with a legal obligation

To use data analytics to improve our website,

products/services, marketing, customer

relationships and experiences

Necessary for our legitimate interests (e.g. to

define types of people for our services, to keep

our website updated and relevant, to develop

our business and to inform our strategy)

To deliver relevant website content to you and

measure or understand the effectiveness of

the content we deliver to you

Necessary for our legitimate interests (e.g. to

study how people use our services, to develop

them, to grow our business and to inform our

strategy)

To deliver direct marketing to you, and to

enable you to partake in a prize draw,

competition or complete a survey

Necessary for our legitimate interests (e.g. for

showcasing our clients or to better understand

how our freelancers/clients use our services)

Where the law exceptionally mandates that we

must obtain your consent for email or text

marketing, our lawful basis will be consent; we

do not require consent for business to

business marketing, but we will always respect

your right to opt out (you can do that by

clicking the link in the footer)

To use aggregate data to publish reports on the

freelance community and advocate for the

freelance community

Necessary for our legitimate interests and

freelancers’ legitimate interests (e.g.

promoting a deeper understanding of

YunoJuno and the wider freelancer community

and their position in the economy and

responding to consultations about the legal

rules as they apply to freelancers and

YunoJuno)

7

4136-3642-7051, v. 1.6

There may also be other purposes where we are permitted to use your personal data which may not

be in the table above, including where you give your consent, where it is necessary to perform or enter

into a contract with you, where it is necessary to comply with a legal obligation, where it is necessary

to protect your or another’s vital interests, or it is otherwise in our legitimate interests to do so under

the General Data Protection Regulation.

Marketing and advertising

We may use your Identity, Contact, Profile, Technical, and Usage Data to form a view on what we think

you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which services, events

or offers may be relevant for you (we call this marketing).

You will receive direct marketing communications from us if you have requested information from

us or if you provided us with your details when you registered with us, completed a survey or entered

a competition (such as the annual Freelancer Awards), and, in each case, you have not opted out of

receiving that marketing.

We may use information which we hold about you to show you relevant advertising on third party

sites, which is known as retargeting. If you do not want to be shown targeted advertising messages

from YunoJuno, some third party sites allow you to request not to see messages from specific

advertisers on that site in future. To learn more about how to control the advertising you receive

outside of our website by going to http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/.

Third-party marketing

We will get your express opt-in consent before we share your contact details with any company

outside YunoJuno for marketing purposes.

Opting out

You can ask us to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by logging into the website and

checking or unchecking relevant boxes to adjust your marketing preferences or by following the

optout links on any marketing message sent to you or by contacting us at any time.

Where you opt out of receiving these marketing messages, this will not affect our use of your personal

data for other purposes. We still need to use your personal data to provide our service to you.

Cookies \& pixels

You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or

access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may

become inaccessible or not function properly.

Please see our Cookie Policy for more detailed information on how we use cookies.

We use Mailchimp to send marketing emails. Mailchimp emails contain pixels that help us

understand our audience better (for example, how many emails were opened, which links in our

emails get clicked, etc). We use this information to help us continuously improve the emails which

we send. If you would like Mailchimp not to collect this type of data from you, you can set your email

settings to receive plain text emails.

Change of purpose

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably

consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original

purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible

with the original purpose, please contact us.

If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain

the legal basis which allows us to do so.

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in

compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

8

4136-3642-7051, v. 1.6

5 DISCLOSURES OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA

We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below.

Internal Third Parties

Other companies in the YunoJuno Group and who are based in the US and undertake leadership

reporting. (To enable us to undertake sharing with the US, we have in place EU Model Clauses, which

are an official mechanic which is permitted under the General Data Protection Regulation to allow

this.)

External Third Parties

• Onfido – our verification partner (identity and right to work)

• Stripe – our payment processor for credit card payments

• Kingsbridge Risk Solutions Limited – our IR35 assessment and insurance partner

• AAB - our inside IR35 payroll partner when paid via YunoJuno

• Giant Business Connect Limited - our Inside IR35 partner (see here for more detail about how

freelancers contract and are paid via Giant for Inside IR35 assignments)

• Technical Service providers:

o Amazon Web Services (EU, covered under UK-EU Treaty) – click here for more

information

o Coralogix (EU, covered under UK-EU Treaty) – click here or more information o

FormBucket – click here for more information o Google (US, covered under Standard

Contractual Clauses) – click here for more information

o Heroku (EU, covered under UK-EU Treaty) – click here for more information o Intercom

(US, covered under Standard Contractual Clauses) – click here or more information

o Mailchimp (US, covered under Standard Contractual Clauses) – click here for more

information

o New Relic (US, covered under Standard Contractual Clauses) – click here or more

information

o Onfido (EU, covered under UK-EU Treaty) – click here for more information o Sentry

(US, covered under Standard Contractual Clauses) – click here for more information

o Sqreen (EU, covered under UK-EU Treaty) – for more information click here for more

information

• Analytics providers (we do not send personally identifiable data and use their IP scrubbing

features to remove technical data):

o Google Analytics – click here for more information o Segment Analytics – click

here for more information o Mailchimp – click here for more information

• Retargeting providers:

o Bing – click here for more information o Google – click here for more

information o LinkedIn – click here for more information o Twitter – click here

for more information

• Professional advisers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers based inside and

outside the UK who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services

• HM Revenue \& Customs (HMRC), regulators and other authorities who require reporting of

processing activities in certain circumstances. (In particular we are legally required to report

9

4136-3642-7051, v. 1.6

freelancer payments to HMRC; HMRC also has international data sharing powers with other

authorities around the world to police tax compliance.)

• Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our

assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a

change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the

same way as set out in this privacy notice

• General public: content on your public profile is on our website, and may be shared by us to

promote us and you, and is available to anyone who accesses it and onward shares it (e.g. via

social media sharing).

Freelancers on our website choose how to arrange their professional lives, and how they provide their

services to their clients. Some choose to join umbrella companies to make their tax affairs simpler.

If you choose to join an umbrella company, we will issue invoices for your services to the umbrella

company. Any use of that information by the umbrella company is governed by your contract with

them, and they have a separate obligation to you to provide you with information about how they use

your personal data. There may be aggregated billing and payment data sharing between YunoJuno

and umbrella companies which is business data not personal data (e.g. an umbrella company’s

aggregated invoice to YunoJuno).

We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance

with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own

purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in

accordance with our instructions. We have detailed Data Processing Agreements in place with Giant

Business Connect Limited and Kingsbridge Risk Solutions Limited.

6 INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS

Some of our external third parties are based outside the United Kingdom (UK) so their processing of

your personal data will involve a transfer of data outside the UK. Some of our clients and freelancers

may be based outside the UK.

Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the UK, we ensure a similar degree of protection is

afforded to it by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:

• We will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been approved by the

Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), which currently includes the European Economic

Area (EEA) and all the countries currently deemed to provide an adequate level of protection

for personal data by the European Commission. Data transfers from the EEA to the UK are

also permitted as the European Commission has determined that the UK has adequacy.

• Where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts approved by the ICO

which give personal data the same protection it has in the UK (called Standard Contractual

Clauses)

• Following the Schrems II case in July 2020, we no longer make data transfers to the US based

on Privacy Shield

7 DATA SECURITY

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being

accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit

access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who

have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions, and they

are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you

and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

10

4136-3642-7051, v. 1.6

8 DATA RETENTION

How long will you use my personal data for?

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it

for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and

sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of

your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can

achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

By law we have to keep basic information about our users (including Contact, Identity, Financial and

Assignment Data) for six years after they cease being users for tax compliance purposes.

In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see Your legal rights below for further

information.

In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated

with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely

without further notice to you.

9 YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS

Under certain circumstances, you have the following rights under data protection laws in relation to

your personal data:

• Request access to your personal data

• Request correction of your personal data

• Request erasure of your personal data

• Object to processing of your personal data

• Request restriction of processing your personal data

• Request transfer of your personal data

• Right to withdraw consent

More details on these rights can be found in the Glossary. If you wish to exercise any of the rights set

out above, please contact us.

You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner's Office (ICO),

the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues (www.ico.org.uk). We would, however,

appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us

in the first instance. Thank you.

No fee usually required

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights).

However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive.

Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

What we may need from you

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure

your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security

measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it.

We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up

our response. Time limit to respond

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer

than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this

case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

11

4136-3642-7051, v. 1.6

10 GLOSSARY

LAWFUL BASIS

Legitimate Interest means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to

enable us to give you the best service/product and the best and most secure experience. We make

sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your

rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal

data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your

consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law). You can obtain further information about

how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific

activities by contacting us.

Performance of Contract means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance of a

contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such a contract.

Comply with a legal or regulatory obligation means processing your personal data where it is

necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to.

YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS

You have the right to:

Request access to your personal data (commonly known as a "data subject access request"). This

enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully

processing it.

Request correction of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any

incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the

accuracy of the new data you provide to us.

Request erasure of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data

where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to

delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to

processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are

required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always

be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you,

if applicable, at the time of your request

Object to processing of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of

a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object

to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You

also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing

purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to

process your information which override your rights and freedoms.

Request restriction of processing of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the

processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data's

accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you

need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend

legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have

overriding legitimate grounds to use it.

Request the transfer of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third

party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format.

Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for

us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.

Withdraw consent at any time where we are relying on consent to process your personal data.

However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your

consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to

you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.
